auctionet.com 2019-05-12

# Privacy policy - Auctionet

## We protect your personal data

It is important to us, at Auction Network Sweden AB, 556859-5150, (“Auctionet”) that you feel secure when it comes to how we process your personal data. Therefore, we are open in regards to how we collect, process and share the data we collect about you. We will never sell your personal data to other companies.  
Personal data is all information that may be used to identify a single individual. Examples of this may be basic information about you, such as name and contact information, but also information abut how you use our digital channels (e.g. our website).  
We make sure that your personal data always is protected and that they are processed in accordance with current regulations for data protection, internal guidelines and procedures.  
In these pages we describe how and why Auctionet process your personal data, as well as your rights.

## Where do we process your personal data?

Your personal data are stored in a so called cloud solution, which means that your personal data may be stored in a country outside of EU/EEC. Regardless of which country your personal data are stored in, we will take all reasonable legal, technical and organisational measures to make sure that the protection level is the same as within EU/EEC. In case personal data are stored outside of EU/EEC the protection level is guaranteed through a decision by the EU commission, that the country in question provides an satisfactory protection level or through the use of adequate protection measures. Example of adequate protection measures are, code of conduct in the receiving country, standard agreement clauses, stringent internal regulations or Privacy Shield. If you would like a copy of the protection measures implemented, or information about where these have been made available, feel free to contact us.

## Updates

We may update this information text, e.g. if we should process your data for new purposes, collect further information, or share your data with other recipients than those stated here. If so you will be provided with an updated information where the changes are implemented. The latest version of the information is always available here on Privacy policy.

## How do we protect personal data

We utilise IT-systems to protect the secrecy, integrity and access to personal data. We have taken special measures in order to protect your personal data from illegal or unauthorised handling (such as illegal access, loss, corruption or damage). Only those who actually need to process your personal data in order to fulfil our stated purposes will have access to them.

Auctionet is responsible for your data being processed in a safe and correct manner.

## Where do we collect personal data?

We collect personal data from:

### You

We collect personal data which you provide us with, and process these when you, e.g. create an account on Auctionet.com, order transport, contact customer service.

### Social media

We collect contact information from Facebook is you use a Facebook registration/login.

### Auction houses

We collect personal data from other action houses about you, as a seller of an item, if you select to connect your Auctionet account with your seller’s account with the action house.

### Partners

When a seller’s account is connected with a buyer's account on Auctionet, the sellers data is collected from the auction house concerned.

## In order to process your purchase

We process your personal data in order to handle your purchase in any action house connected to our services and arrange for the services you order, such as transport and delivery, and in order to be able to receive payment. We also process your personal data in order to check status of payment and to get information about time of purchase and place of purchase in order to enable delivery as well as ordering pick up of purchased item.

**Categories of personal data**

  * Name
  * Personal identification number
  * Contact information (e.g. address, e-mail and phone number)
  * Payment information.
  * Payment history.
  * Any comments you post.
  * Sellers information when connecting seller’s and buyer’s accounts.

**Legal basis** : _Agreement_. The handling is necessary in order to fulfil the agreement with you.

**Storage period** : Until the purchase is completed (including delivery and payment) and for a period of 36 months thereafter in order to handle any complaint and warranty matters.

## In order to communicate with you and handle customer service issues

We process your personal data in order to communicate with you, e.g. send transaction notifications (for example if you have been outbid, won an auction or in order to issue invoice for purchased items, as well as instructions for the use of the service), communicate with you regarding questions you ask and to handle other customer service issues.

**Categories of personal data**

  * Name
  * Personal identification number
  * Contact information (e.g. address, e-mail and phone number)
  * Payment information.
  * Payment history.
  * Any information you provide.

**Legal basis** : _Legitimate interest_. The processing is necessary to satisfy our and our customer's legitimate interest in evaluating, developing and improving our services, products and systems as described above.

**Storage period** : Until the customer service issue is completed and for a period of 36 months thereafter in order to handle any complaint and warranty matters.

We process your personal data for adaptation of services in order to be more user friendly (e.g. change the user interface to simplify the flow of information or to highlight features that often are used by customers of our digital channels). Furthermore we use your personal data as a foundation to improve the flow of goods and logistics (e.g. through forecasting purchases, stock and deliveries) as well as to create a basis for development and improvement of our services.

The data are also used to create a basis for developing and improving our resource efficiency from a environment and sustainability perspective (e.g. through streamlining purchasing and planning of deliveries) to create a basis with the intent to plan for new and any discontinuing of auction houses and warehouses.  
We even give our clients the possibility to influence our selection of services and we create a basis for improvement of our IT-system for the purpose of increasing the security of the company and our visitors/clients.

Based on the information we gather (e.g. purchase history, age and gender), we perform an analysis which may result in you being placed in a client group (client segment), but the analysis is never performed on an individual level. The results of the analysis forms the basis for which products to be purchased and how we develop the service Auctionet.com.

**Categories of personal data**

  * Age.
  * Gender.
  * Hometown.
  * Correspondence and feedback regarding our services and products.
  * Purchase and user generated data (e.g. click and visit history).
  * Technical data regarding devices being used and their settings (e.g. language settings, IP address, browser settings, time zone, operative system, screen resolution and platform).
  * Information about how you interacted with us, i.e. how you have used the service, method of login, where and how long various sites have been visited, response times, how you reach and leave the service, etc.

**Legal basis** : _Legitimate interest_. The processing is necessary to satisfy our and our customer's legitimate interest in evaluating, developing and improving our services, products and systems as described above.

**Storage period:** : From gathering and for a period of 36 months thereafter in order to improve our services based on how users utilises the service.

We process your personal data for prevention and investigation of any fraud or other violations (e.g. bid tampering where the seller bid on his own auction in order to rise the final bid in an auction). Furthermore, your personal data is processed to prevent spam, phishing, harassment, attempts of illegal login to user accounts or other actions which are prohibited by law or in violation of out terms and conditions. We also use personal data for improvement of our IT environment regarding protection against attacks and intrusions.

**Categories of personal data**

  * Personal identification number to ensure that an account is unique to one individual.
  * Purchase and user generated data (e.g. click and visit history).
  * Technical data regarding devices being used and their settings (e.g. language settings, IP address, browser settings, time zone, operative system, screen resolution and platform).
  * Information regarding how our digital services are being used.

**Legal basis** : _Legal obligation and legitimate interest_. Compliance with legal obligation (if such exist). If no legal obligation exists, processing is necessary to satisfy our legitimate interest in avoiding abuse of a service or to avoid, prevent and investigate crimes against the company.

**Storage period** : From gathering and for a period of 36 months, in order to avoid abuse of our services and to avoid, prevent and investigate crimes against the company.

We process your personal data to enable you to make personal settings regarding your profile and your personal choices, create login feature, secure your identity and age, as well as enable you to keep track of your purchase and payment history. We also need your personal data to enable you to save favourites and handle similar facilitation measures for your use of the service, as well as being able to handle your choices (e.g. your profile and settings regarding notifications, settings for marketing). Finally, we process your personal data to be able to connect buyer and seller accounts.

**Categories of personal data**

  * Name.
  * Personal identification number.
  * Contact information (e.g. address, e-mail and phone number).
  * Purchase history.
  * Payment history.
  * Payment information.
  * Username and password.
  * Seller information as well as contact and product information from the auction house.

**Legal basis** : _Agreement_. This gathering of your personal data is required for us to be able to fulfil our obligations in accordance with the terms and conditions for use. If the information is not given our obligations can not be fulfilled and we are forced to deny your membership. The seller information is voluntary, but is required for us to be able to fulfil our obligations in accordance with terms and conditions for use when connecting buyer ans seller accounts.

**Storage period** : From collection and for a period of 36 months thereafter, in order to create My Pages and administrate your membership.

We process your personal data in order to provide you with personalised content in the service, such as by providing you with relevant product recommendations, offers and other similar features which simplify your use (e.g. through saving favourites or searches to simplify future purchases or remind you of objects whose end time is approaching).

We also process your personal data in order to provide you with a personalised communication based on your membership behaviour.

In order to be able to provide a personalised service and communication, analysis may be made at an individual level, e.g. through analysis of purchase and bidding history leading to product recommendations. The results of the analysis forms the basis for our communication with you and which offer, products and information will be presented to you in,for example, My pages.

Keep in mind that you can, at any time, reserve yourself from direct marketing by marking this via link in respective e-mails, as well as oppose to profiling for the same purpose.

**Categories of personal data**

  * Name.
  * Username.
  * Contact information (e.g. address, e-mail and phone number).
  * Age.
  * Gender.
  * Hometown.
  * IP address.
  * Purchase history.
  * Purchase and user generated data (e.g. click and visit history).
  * Entered client choices regarding communication channels.

**Legal basis** : _Agreement_. Completion of membership agreement. This gathering of your personal data is required for us to fulfil our obligations in accordance with the membership agreement, as well as completing ordered services such as selection of the service Favourites or Saved searches, If the information is not given our obligations can not be fulfilled.

**Storage period** : Until the membership is terminated.

## To determine, enforce and exercise legal claims

We process your information with the intention of determining, enforcing and exercising legal claims, e.g. to handle complaints and claims and in accordance with a court process.

**Categories of personal data**

  * Name
  * Contact information (e.g. phone number, e-mail address)
  * Purchase history
  * Communication with customer service.
  * Information regarding payment or settlement.

**Legal basis** : _Legitimate interest_. The processing is necessary in order to satisfy our legitimate interest in determining, enforcing and exercising legal claims.

**Storage period** : Your personal data will be retained for the period of time where we or you may raise legal claims against us, i.e. until the limitation period expires.

## To fulfil legal obligations

We process your personal data in order to fulfil legal obligations that we have, for example, keeping you information updated and correct in accordance with data protection legislation and to comply with regulations for accounting.

**Categories of personal data**

  * Name
  * Contact information (e.g. phone number, e-mail address)
  * Personal identification number
  * Information regarding payment and settlement.

**Legal basis** : _Legal obligation_. The processing is necessary in order for us to fulfil our legal obligations.

**Storage period** : Your personal data will be retained for the period of time required in accordance with the legal obligation, for example, accounting material is kept for seven years.

We will only process your personal identification number when it is clearly motivated for the purpose, necessary for secure identification, or if there is any other reasonable reason. We will always minimise the use of your personal identification number as much as possible by, where this is adequate, utilize your date of birth instead.

In some cases we need to share your personal data with others, for example, in order to provide our services.

We share personal data with:

## Service providers

These companies may only use your personal data in accordance with our instructions and are not allowed to use your information for their own purposes.

**Category of service provider**

  * Companies who helps us with marketing, for example, print and distribution, media agencies and advertising agencies.
  * Companies who provide IT services, for example, operations, technical support and maintenance of our IT systems.
  * Companies who provide payment solutions (card provider companies, banks and other payment providers).
  * Transport companies within logistic and freight forwarding

## Other recipients

In some cases Auction Network Sweden AB may share your personal data with other recipients who them selves are responsible for personal data. When your personal data is shared with a recipient who is personal data responsible the recipients policy for integrity and processing of personal data will apply.

Recipient | Purpose | Legal justification for the transfer  
---|---|---  
Transport companies | We share address information as well as phone number with companies who handles logistics and freight forwarding. | Agreement. The processing is necessary in order for the product you have purchased to be delivered.  
Authorities | We may give necessary information to the authorities if we are obligated by law to do so. | Legal obligation. The processing is necessary in order for us to fulfil legal obligations.  
External advisors | We may give necessary information to external advisors, such as accounting agencies, lawyer offices or other law firms if we are obligated by law to do so, or to handle or handle or respond to legal claims. | Legal obligation and legitimate interest. The processing is necessary to fulfil legal obligations or to satisfy our legitimate interest to manage and respond to legal claims.  
Court of law, counterparties etc. | To handle and respond to legal claims we may transfer information to third parties. | Legitimate interest. The processing is necessary to satisfy our legitimate interest to manage and respond to legal claims.  
Law enforcement authorities, e.g. the police. | We may share personal data with law enforcement authorities, e.g. the police, if we are obligated by law to do so or to contribute to an ongoing criminal investigation. | Legal obligation and legitimate interest. The processing is necessary to fulfil legal obligations or to satisfy our legitimate interest to contribute to ongoing criminal investigation upon request.  
Action houses that are connected to our services. | We share personal data with selling auction house when you, as a buyer, has won an auction. | Legitimate interest. In order for the auction house to know if the item has been paid in full and to ensure that the item is delivered to the correct person.  
Potential buyers and sellers. | We may share information with potential buyers or sellers if we should sell all, or parts, of the company, or in case of a merger. | Legitimate interest. The processing is necessary to satisfy our legitimate interest to complete the divestment or merger.  
  
Read more about how we use cookies in our [cookie policy](https://auctionet.com/help/90-cookies).

You have certain rights regarding your personal data stored by us. You have, for example, the right to get a printout of the personal data stored about you and to have your information corrected.

You can read more about the Data Protection Ordinance and which rights you have on the Data Inspectorate’s website.

You have the right to:

## Gain access to your personal data

It is important for us to be open and transparent in regards to what information we collect about you. As a member of Auctionet you may, at any time, log inn to My Pages to see what information we have registered about you, e.g. contact information.

You may also gain access to your information by requesting a printout of the personal data we have registered about you as well as requesting a digital copy. Contact [dataskydd@auctionet.com](mailto:dataskydd@auctionet.com).

## Requesting correction of personal data

If you consider any information about you to be incorrect or incomplete, you have the right to request that this information is corrected or completed. Keep in mind that you, as a member of Auctionet, can change all your personal data directly via My Pages. You can also contact us at [dataskydd@auctionet.com](mailto:dataskydd@auctionet.com).

## Giving and revoking your consent

In some cases we will ask you to give your consent to process your personal data. You then have the right to, at any time, change you mind and revoke this consent for continuous processing. Contact [dataskydd@auctionet.com](mailto:dataskydd@auctionet.com) if you wish to revoke a given consent.

## Reject direct advertising

You may, at any time, reject advertising and communications distribution, both digital and in paper format. The right to reject also includes analysis of personal data (so called profiling) performed for direct marketing purposes. Direct marketing refers to all types of outreach promotional actions (e.g. by mail, email and SMS).

Keep in mind that you are always able to influence which channels we use for mailing and personal offers. For example, you can choose to only receive offers from us via email, but not SMS/notifications. In that case, you should not object to personal data processing as such but instead restrict our communication channels (by changing the settings on My Pages).

## Oppose to processing that is supported by our legitimate interest

In some cases, we have assessed that our need to process your personal data is so strong that we have a so called legitimate interest. You are entitled to oppose our assessment of legitimate interest for reasons related to your situation. You can do so by contacting us at [dataskydd@auctionet.com](mailto:dataskydd@auctionet.com).

If there are compelling legitimate reasons for the processing in question that are more important than your integrity, we may continue to process your data, even if you have opposed to this processing. If we can not document compelling reasons, we will stop processing your personal data.

## Deleting data

Under specific circumstances, you have the right to request your personal data to be deleted. If there, for example, no longer is any need to process your personal data or if you have rejected direct advertising. If we need the information to be able to complete an agreement with you or if we are legally obligated to retain personal data, we can not delete them. Contact [dataskydd@auctionet.com](mailto:dataskydd@auctionet.com)

## Limiting processing of data

You have the right to request that the processing of your personal data be limited if you, for example, do not believe they are correct or if you wish to oppose to our legitimate interest in the processing. However, this may mean that we can not fulfil our obligations towards you while the processing is limited. Contact [dataskydd@auctionet.com](mailto:dataskydd@auctionet.com)

## Moving your data (data portability)

You have the right to get a copy of the personal data relating to you in a structured, machine-readable format. Unlike a registry excerpt, this only include some of the information you have provided, for example: If you have submitted your e-mail address when registering for mailing. I other words, only certain data are covered by the right for data portability. Contact [dataskydd@auctionet.com](mailto:dataskydd@auctionet.com)

## Automated decision making

You have the right not to be subjected to automated decision making, including profiling, if such decision making could have legal consequences or similarly significant effect. However, this right is not applicable if the automated decision making is necessary to fulfil an agreement with you, if the decision making is expressly permitted by law or if you have given your explicit consented to this.

If you have any questions regarding the processing of your personal data you are free to contact us. Contact information is stated below. If you are not satisfied with the response you have been given, you have the right to file a complaint with the regulatory authority (Data inspectorate).

Auction Network Sweden AB  
556859-5150  
Grev Turegatan 44  
114 38 Stockholm  
Telephone: +46 (0)8-12449985  
E-mail: [support@auctionet.com](mailto:support@auctionet.com)

Data protection issues:  
Telephone: +46 (0)8-12449985  
E-mail: [dataskydd@auctionet.com](mailto:dataskydd@auctionet.com)

Last updated: 2018-05-25.
